I fell to the broadcast before going
live good time so I just did a scope
pretty much saying these same things it
was 20 minutes long I'm hoping to keep
this under 5 minutes
the only reason I'm not doing a normal
video and live is that my kid is home
for a PD day and she has the iPad so
this is my version this is what I have
available so reading the extinction
rebellions demands which are as follows
I think we can do them all now
I don't think we need to do the arduous
process let's just read them their
demands are to tell the truth they want
our governments must tell the truth by
declaring a climate and ecological
emergency working with other
institutions to communicate the urgency
of change - they want us to act now so
they want our governments to act now so
that we reach Net Zero by 2025 they want
citizens and then the third point is
beyond politics what their governments
must create and be led on these
decisions by a citizen's assembly on
climate change in ecological justice all
of their demands require that we our
governments take action yet at the same
time the third citizens assembly is that
governments aren't effective at taking
actions they have to be able to listen
to the people because you can't have
change happen every four to five years
when you know we need two things we need
a very long term plan to be enacted
because climate change is a long-term
plan and we need to be able to be swift
and taking action on everything we do
and the ripple effects that happen right
away our governments are not designed
for either of those things they're not
quick enough for the momentary and
they're not they don't have a long-term
vision because they're voted in every
four years but we can do what these
demands now ourselves we can hold a
citizen's assembly by creating the idea
cafe online and I have a slightly
different version that we which is the
documents in this description that we
host a idea cafe every four hours so six
times lots in a 24 hour period so that
for your time zone one of those is going
to work for you every one of those six
time slots we hold for an hour so if you
come on in participate you can have one
in a second conversation each
conversation you are sat at a table
table a virtual table with three to five
other people and you're answering that
day's question a question is held for 48
hours we generate the questions the
powerful question that we want to
discuss and then the third day is held
for harvesting the conversations so you
can participate in none of them or you
can participate in up to 24 2010 24 hour
period that's 12 times slots times 2 I
believe that's yet 24 24 time slots if
you wanted to but that would involve
being awake every 4 hours for an hour so
I would highly suggest not to do that I
would suggest just having a conversation
in the time slots that work for you and
you can have you can easily do 4 if
you're available for just one of those
time slots because each one is just
whatever it's a little more explained in
the document that I promised in the
description through those conversations
we can do demands wanting to we can
create the method to tell the truth
because right now even greta tomb Berg's
option is like going through the
research everyone should do the research
I don't think everyone should do the
research because even if you know all of
the research you then just like lose
help and feel hopeless like now you know
that we're all headed towards extinction
fighting in a world where not everyone
knows we have to make the information
understandable and usable and accessible
to all which means we have to have a
citizen's assembly like what is the
citizen's assembly gonna do they're
gonna need to understand the complex
information they're gonna need to
compile the science they're gonna need
to make the science understandable to at
least 100 of them and then they're gonna
need to be able to somewhat disseminate
that to the public we can do that way
more effectively together not with a
hundred people not with our governments
taking forever to take action and
spending way too much money doing that
that they will have to fight against all
the other things that we want our
taxpayers to go to taxpayer dollars we
can just create the citizens assembly we
can compile the information even if
nobody externally believes it we can
create the information that gives us
access to climate change information to
ecological crisis information in a way
that we trust and then everyone that
comes on board after you can see the
transparent paths of information that we
created we can
now NetZero by 2025 we're almost at 2020
our governments aren't designed to take
swift action and they're not designed
for all of the fallout that's gonna
happen we need to be able to create the
system to be able to deal with that to
be able to constantly ask people if we
want them to take action on a certain
thing what action to take and then when
they tell us oh I can't do that because
of XYZ giving them solutions we need a
much more resilient system than the one
we currently have and we can do that by
creating a citizen's assembly on zoom in
it or existing on existing technology
and then once there's enough of us doing
that or enough of us participating in
that conversation we create the platform
design for that conversation and then we
use it to tackle every single issue
people can come on and have an idea Cafe
otherwise known as a conversation around
a meaningful question where we take
turns answering it and then harvest it
for information
maybe not otherwise I myself that's he's
a little more complex that we can create
all of what extinction rebellions
demands are right now collectively
without requiring first that our
government step in because all of these
things the government needing to do it
we can just do it and it's getting much
more effective coming from us instead of
us demanding each one of our
democratically elected governments they
clearly aren't democracies not really
they're not working in our best interest
change everything they've been doing for
decades
start acting our own interest do
citizens assemblies listen to the
citizens assemblies and then the
Canadian government listening to the
Canadian citizen assembly talks to the
American government listening to the
American citizens assembly - you don't
say all of those people talking to each
other and very expensive very polluting
climate summits we the people just have
these citizens assembly we don't need
the Canadian citizen assembly in the
American the Australian we need the
global citizens assembly to say how do
we understand this what is currently
happening and we're solve this all the
co2 coming from all the pollution we're
going to much more be able to create the
tools to be able to tackle those
problems together to be able to trust
the information coming out of them and
we can do it all together rather easily
once we have the tools to be able to
have
conversation and harvest that
conversation and put people where they
want to go so that they're talking about
things that are passionate that they're
impassioned by things that they care
about things they want to spend their
time understand understanding and
tackling and then we we like literally
unleash humanity on humanity's problems
that is what the global tech cooperative
did I had vision in my head well now is
going to and is like it's going to do it
you're going to do it together this is
just one iteration of what we can
actually do together we can create a
citizen's assembly tomorrow sign up for
like zoo I did the time slot so you can
click on it and see what times thought
it is in your area people jump on the
worst that happens is they have more
than a hundred people because that's all
they can can consume darn it
then we need more people to sign up for
zoom we need a we need a way to be able
to get people to the right so you can
call somebody I can't do that
I can barely I was like I needed stream
yarn tool to figure out how to do idea
cafe on YouTube and now that I've had
idea cafe on YouTube for like this is
the third week on Wednesday will be the
third week I'm like let's just like
create a citizen's assembly for all of
climate change but I don't know how to
get people to the right one until we
have the platform that actually works
for it but somebody out there does
somebody else can create that in a
weekend create the way the beta platform
that I envisioned in my head for what
zoom is gonna do for us to get people to
the right zoom call someone could do in
a weekend probably for under like if we
pooled our money together and I'm
actually on the word
I'm co-opting someone's brain this
Wednesday well I'm cooking with him I'm
like by the way I'm just gonna you
realize I have an idea I'm gonna ask you
a how we actually create this thing so I
will have a better idea of what this
would actually cost to be made in
Vancouver that's the most expensive
place to make it like you don't pay
people anyway whatever I've been on for
longer than I meant to be on I just
wanted to come on and say there's a way
we can hold a citizen's assembly now in
the description is what I propose for a
zoom conversation or how we hold a
citizen's assembly that works across the
globe in all different time zones
I sadly have stated that we're gonna
start it in English because until we
have the platform I don't know how we
hosted in many different languages it's
hard enough getting people to the
different timeslots without also
focusing on different languages but once
we have the platform like yes the beta
platform needs to deal with multiple
languages and possibly as somebody who
takes this and releases it in Cantonese
and Punjabi and Hindi like yes do that
do that it's not it's not my propriety
well I guess it is my proprietary idea
I'm unpretending it take it go with it
but I can't create it for all of those
languages yeah anyway so we create
citizens assembly and then create the
platform designed for those type of
conversations now today and I'm gonna go
now before I keep rambling on till the
30th minute